<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ian</title>
    <link>http://goian.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ian</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 16:35:43 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://goian.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics</title>
      <link>http://goian.io/basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 16:35:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://goian.io/basics/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 1 Basics Discover what this ian is all about and the core-concepts behind it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is this Ian ?</title>
      <link>http://goian.io/basics/what-is-ian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://goian.io/basics/what-is-ian/</guid>
      <description>Ian is a simple tool to manage your development environment and your coding projects.
The idea behind Ian Us, developers, love to work with the terminal. More reliable and simpler than most GUIs, this &amp;ldquo;black screen&amp;rdquo; allows also automation through scripting and blazing fast manipulation.
But even with these capabilities, we still execute pretty repetitive tasks and have troubles to make our local environment portable. Sometimes, we&amp;rsquo;re looking in our history to retrieve a database URI, change from one project directory to another one just to execute a command, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started</title>
      <link>http://goian.io/basics/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 16:36:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://goian.io/basics/getting-started/</guid>
      <description> Installation Installing ian is pretty straightforward. All you have to do is to paste this in your terminal:
# Bash/Zsh sudo python -c &amp;quot;$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/thylong/ian/master/install/install.py)&amp;quot; # Fish sudo python -c &amp;quot;(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/thylong/ian/master/install/install.py)&amp;quot;  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration</title>
      <link>http://goian.io/basics/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 16:36:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://goian.io/basics/configuration/</guid>
      <description>Ian relies a lot on configuration files as they describe your environment and your projects. It&amp;rsquo;s possible to edit your entire configuration using ian commands (recommended) but if you&amp;rsquo;re stuck or if you simply prefer to edit manually your configuration, it&amp;rsquo;s possible !
Ian configuration files are written with Yaml and are relatively simple to read. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have specific ian files, no worries some are going to be generated for you when you execute it for the first time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changelog</title>
      <link>http://goian.io/changelog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 16:36:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://goian.io/changelog/</guid>
      <description>The CHANGELOG of the project can be seen here: https://github.com/thylong/ian/releases</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributing</title>
      <link>http://goian.io/contributing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 16:36:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://goian.io/contributing/</guid>
      <description>Any contribution to this project is more than welcomed ! As small or big as they are, contributions are what will make this project better. There is still a lot to do : reporting bugs, proposing fixes, new features, helping with the documentation&amp;hellip;
If it’s your first contribution, no worries. As long as you follow the guidelines, everything is going to be fine :)
Open an issue If you spot a bug or want to propose an enhancement, you can open an issue on Github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>http://goian.io/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 16:36:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://goian.io/license/</guid>
      <description>Apache License Version 2.0, January 2004 http://www.apache.org/licenses/
TERMS AND CONDITIONS FOR USE, REPRODUCTION, AND DISTRIBUTION
 Definitions.
&amp;ldquo;License&amp;rdquo; shall mean the terms and conditions for use, reproduction, and distribution as defined by Sections 1 through 9 of this document.
&amp;ldquo;Licensor&amp;rdquo; shall mean the copyright owner or entity authorized by the copyright owner that is granting the License.
&amp;ldquo;Legal Entity&amp;rdquo; shall mean the union of the acting entity and all other entities that control, are controlled by, or are under common control with that entity.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>